[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
[ Symphony orchestra plays ]
Baltimore , Md 1980
LECTER : " Think to yourself that every day is your last ...
" the hour to which you do not look forward ...
" will come as a welcome surprise .
" As for me ...
" when you want a good laugh ...
" you will find me , in a fine state ...
" fat and sleek ...
" a true hog of Epicurus ' herd . "
[ Laughter ]
And we find you cribbing lines from Horace , as well .
Well done , John .
I must say , Hannibal ...
speaking for the rest of the herd ...
I 'm sorry , for the Symphony Board ...
that these little soirees of yours ...
are always the highlight of our year .
- Just so . - You 're too kind .
I do feel guilty enjoying tonight when a musician is ...
still listed as a missing person .
Yes , poor fellow .
MAN : Shall I confess something wicked ?
I can 't help feeling the tiniest bit ... relieved .
It sounds awful , I know .
But , let 's face it , so does the man 's playing .
Hannibal , confess .
What is this divine-looking amuse-bouche ?
If I tell you ...
I 'm afraid you won 't even try it .
[ Laughter ]
- Bon appétit . - Bon appétit .
[ Doorbell rings ]
Special Agent Graham . What an unexpected pleasure .
I 'm sorry to bother you again , Dr. Lecter. I know it 's late .
It 's no bother . We 're both night owls , I think .
- Come in , please . - Thank you .
Let me take your coat .
LECTER : What 's on your mind ?
We 've been on the wrong track this whole time . You and I .
Our whole profile 's wrong .
We 've been looking for someone with a crazy grudge ...
and some kind of anatomical knowledge .
Decertified doctors , med school dropouts ...
laid-off mortuary workers- -
From the precision of the cuts , and his choice of souvenirs .
That 's where we 're off-target .
He 's not collecting body parts .
- Then why keep them ? - He 's not . He 's eating them .
No , listen . We were at Molly 's parents ' for New Year 's ...
and her dad was showing my son , Josh ...
how to carve a roasted chicken .
He said , " The tenderest part of the chicken is the oysters ...
" on either side of the back . "
I had never heard that expression before , " oysters . "
Then suddenly I had a flash of the third victim ...
Darcy Taylor .
She was missing flesh from her back . And then it hit me .
Liver , kidney , tongue , thymus .
Every single victim lost some body part used in cooking .
Have you shared this with the Bureau ?
No , I needed to see you first . But I 'm right. I know I 'm right .
I 'm starting to be able to think like this one .
Yeah , it 's fascinating .
You know , I 'd always suspected as much . You are an eidetiker .
I 'm not psychic , Doctor .
No , this is different .
More akin to artistic imagination .
You can assume the emotional point of view of others ...
even those that might scare or sicken you .
It 's a troubling gift , I should think .
How I 'd love to get you on my couch .
Something still doesn 't make sense to me .
You 're the best forensic psychiatrist I know ...
and somehow , in all our time together ...
this possibility never occurred to you .
I am only human , Will . Perhaps I made a mistake .
You don 't strike me as a man who makes very many mistakes .
Now I 'm sorry to think I might ...
no longer enjoy your full confidence .
No , I didn 't say that .
I don 't know what I 'm saying .
I 'm very , very tired .
I almost had it .
It 'll come to you .
Why don 't you come back in the morning ?
I 'll clear some time on my schedule and ...
then we can get started in revising our profile .
LECTER : Sound good ? will : Yeah .
LECTER : Rest here , and I 'll get your coat .
Won 't be a tick .
[ Slow instrumental music ]
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
[ Climactic instrumental music ]
[ Book slams shut ]
[ Lecter hisses ]
Don 't move .
You 're in shock now. I don 't want you to feel any pain .
In a moment you 'll begin to be light-headed . Then drowsy .
Don 't resist. it 's so gentle . Like slipping into a warm bath .
[ Will gasps in pain ]
I regret it came to this , Will .
But every game must have its ending .
[ Eerie instrumental music ]
LECTER : Remarkable boy .
I do admire your courage .
I think I 'll eat your heart .
[ Lecter gasps ]
[ Dizzying instrumental music ]
[ Rising instrumental music ]
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
[ Eerie instrumental music ]
[ Seagulls crying ]
Marathon , Fl Several Years Later
JOSH : Hey , Dad . Someone 's here .
Hey .
CRAWFORD : You 've got a beautiful set-up here , Will .
will : Yeah , it 's good .
- You know why I 'm here ? - Yeah , I can guess .
How much do you know ?
Just what was in the Miami Herald and the Times .
Two families killed a month apart in their homes .
Birmingham and Atlanta . The circumstances were similar .
Not similar . The same .
What have you kept out of the papers ?
He smashes mirrors and uses the pieces .
Wears latex gloves , so we 've got no prints . Size 1 1 shoe .
He 's not too comfortable with locks .
Pried open a patio door in Birmingham ...
used a glass cutter in Atlanta .
And his blood 's AB positive .
- Somebody hurt him ? - Nope .
We typed him from semen and saliva . He 's a secretor .
Tell me something , Will . You knew what this was .
Did you ever consider picking up the phone and giving me a call ?
You 've got all the people you need .
You 've got Dortmund at Harvard . You got Bloom in Chicago .
I 've got you down here fixing boat motors ?
Yeah , I like fixing boat motors .
I wouldn 't be very useful to you .
I don 't think about it anymore .
Really ? The last two we had , you caught .
By doing what you and the other guys are doing .
That 's not entirely true . It 's the way you think .
Come on . There 's been a lot of bullshit about the way I think .
I 've got technicians to examine evidence ...
but you 've got that other thing .
Imagination . Projection . Whatever .
- l know you don 't like it . - You wouldn 't like it , either .
[ Moving instrumental music ]
This freak killed the Jacobis in Birmingham ...
on Saturday night , February 25 . Full moon .
He killed the Leeds family in Atlanta ...
a few nights ago , March 28 .
One day short of a lunar month .
If we 're lucky , we may have a little over three weeks ...
before he does it again .
Will , do you respect my judgment ?
Of course .
I think we have a better chance to catch him fast if you help .
Go to Atlanta and look . Just look .
Then help me brief the locals . That 's it .
MOLLY : Crawford has the whole damn government .
Why does he need you ?
He just wants me to look at some evidence , Molly .
Give him another point of view .
It 's a few days , a week maybe , and I 'll be right back .
- And you believed that ? - Yes .
These kinds of cases come up very rarely ...
and I 've had experience .
Yes , you have .
You 're paid up , Will .
All of us . Even Josh .
There 's a chance I could help them save some lives .
How do I say no to that ?
This one will never see me or know my name .
I 'll just help them find him .
The cops will take him down , not me .
I 'll be in the back of the pack , Molly , I promise .
Never in your life .
[ Tender instrumental music ]
- l know you . - Come on . Come here .
will : I love you .
will : See you in a few days . JOSH : Okay .
will : I 'll call you tonight .
[ Car engine starts up ]
JOSH : ' Bye , Dad !
[ Melancholy instrumental music ]
Leeds House , Atlanta , Ga
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
Where 's the dog ? No one heard barking .
There 's nothing about it in the case file .
[ Tense instrumental music ]
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
The intruder enters in the dark and cuts Charles Leeds ' throat .
He shoots Valerie Leeds in the stomach as she 's rising ...
disabling her but not killing her .
He leaves her to watch her husband die ...
then turns and goes down the hall .
[ Eerie instrumental music ]
The children were ... .
The children were still in bed when they were shot ...
which might indicate that he used a silencer .
He dragged the bodies into the master bedroom , but why ?
They were already dead and none of them got the same ...
extra attention as Mrs. Leeds .
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
Small pieces of mirror were inserted ...
in the orbital sockets of the victims .
This occurred post-mortem .
Why did you put mirrors in their eyes ?
[ Warped child 's cry ]
[ Climactic instrumental music ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Fabric tearing ]
[ Heartbeats ]
The pieces of mirror are to make their eyes look alive !
He wanted an audience . He wanted them all lined up ...
watching him when he touched her .
When he touched her .
Touched . Talcum powder .
There was talcum powder .
will : " Mrs. Leeds had traces of talcum on her right inner thigh .
" A complete search of the home ...
" led to no such matching talcum in the house . "
You took your gloves off , didn 't you ? You son of a bitch !
You took your gloves off , touched her ...
with your bare hand and wiped her down .
But when the gloves were off , did you open her eyes ?
[ Telephone rings ]
Crawford .
will : Are the Leeds ' bodies still at the morgue ?
Who 's good with latent prints here ?
CRAWFORD : Atlanta P.D.
They 've already printed the bodies .
Not the bodies . Tell them to check the eyes .
Mrs. Leeds ' eyes . Even her corneas .
I think he took his gloves off . I think he had to touch her .
Jesus , Will .
PRlNCl : Gentlemen . Ladies .
This is what the subject 's teeth look like .
The impressions came from bite marks on Mrs. Leeds .
This degree of crookedness ...
plus the groove in this central incisor ...
makes his bite signature unique .
Fuckin ' shark .
springfield : Knock it off !
We 're grateful to have the fbi .
They have a lot of expertise in this area .
In particular , lnvestigator Graham does .
That right , Jack ?
Yes , sir .
Anything you want to add , Mr. Graham ?
commissioner : Why don 't you come on up to the front , please ?
[ Cops murmur ]
COP 1 : That 's the guy . COP 2 : Was he ?
COP 3 : Yeah , that 's the guy who arrested Lecter .
COP 4 : I thought he retired .
COP 5 : The son of a bitch just about gutted him .
Mrs. Leeds and Mrs. Jacobi were the primary targets .
The others were killed just to complete his fantasy .
will : I know that might be hard to accept given what you saw ...
but this was not random .
This wasn 't some killing frenzy . He was never out of control .
These attacks were organised , the women carefully chosen .
We don 't know how he 's choosing them , or why .
They lived in different states and never met .
But there is some connection .
There 's some common factor , and that 's the key .
Find out what that is , and we 'll save lives .
'Cause this one is gonna go on and on ...
until we get smart or we get lucky .
He won 't stop .
- Why not ? - Because it makes him God .
Would you give that up ?
You asked about the dog . Last night a vet called us .
Leeds and his oldest boy brought the dog in ...
the afternoon before they were killed .
Had a puncture wound to its abdomen .
The vet had to put it down .
Was it wearing a collar with the address on it ?
No .
- Did the Jacobis have a dog ? - No dog .
They found a litter box in the basement ...
cat droppings in it , no cat .
If the cat was attacked , the Jacobis may have buried it .
Ask Birmingham to check that backyard .
And tell them to use a methane probe , it 's faster .
[ Telephone rings ]
Yeah. lt 's for you .
Crawford .
Carl , you 're the light of my life .
Would it hold up in court ?
Okay . Great work .
They found a print on Mrs. Leeds ' eye . Partial thumb .
Besides that , there 's nothing else to tell you .
Thank you for your time .
commissioner : I can 't answer more questions .
Will Graham ! Remember me ?
Freddy Lounds. I covered the Lecter case for the Tattler .
- Did the paperback . - Yeah , I remember .
When did they bring you in ? What 've you got ?
You think the Tooth Fairy will be bigger than Lecter ?
I mean , he 's already beaten Lecter 's score- -
You write lying shit , and the Tattler is an asswipe !
You stay away from me .
Get away , Lounds .
How about an exclusive ?
Sorry about that .
That guy snuck into the hospital and took those pictures of me .
Remember ? With the tubes hanging out of me ?
Forget that prick .
CRAWFORD : Give yourself some credit .
When we catch the Tooth Fairy ...
that print plus his teeth will burn him .
You did that , Will .
That evidence was there , Jack .
- lt was there for anyone to see . - But nobody else did .
All I 'm sayin ' is , that was very good work .
No , good work would be seeing it all the way through ...
and catching the guy .
And I can 't do that . I did what you asked me to do .
I 'm going home .
I don 't even have any idea who this guy is .
What I just gave them was broad strokes . He 's got no face to me .
That 's what you said about Garrett Hobbs , remember ?
- And you figured him out . - No , I didn 't .
- You didn 't ? - No , I was stuck on Hobbs .
I had help .
From Lecter .
will : Yeah .
Jack , don 't play games with me . Don 't do it .
Just tell me what 's on your mind .
I 'm saying maybe we 've got a resource we should look into .
is that what this was about ?
Did you just want to ask me that all along ?
Don 't get mad at me . I 'm just doing my job .
If you know a better shortcut , let me know it .
If you think there 's any chance he 'll talk to me ...
I 'll go myself .
If you can 't handle it , God knows I 'd understand that .
CHlLTON : As a research subject , Lecter has proven most disappointing .
He 's simply impenetrable to psychological testing .
Rorschach , Thematic Apperception .
He folds them into origami .
CHlLTON : As you see .
So you can imagine the stir your little visit ...
is causing among my staff , Mr. Graham .
If you 'd care to share some insights- -
Dr. Chilton , I 'm sorry , I 've got a 4 : 1 7 flight back to Atlanta .
Of course .
Tell me , when you saw Lecter 's murders ...
their style , so to speak ...
were you able , perhaps , to reconstruct his fantasies ?
And , if so , did you jot down any impressions ?
will : No .
Let me be frank , Mr. Graham .
The first analysis of Lecter will be a publisher 's wet dream .
I 'd give you full credit , of course .
Damn it , man . You must have some advice . You caught him .
What was your trick ?
I let him kill me .
[ Door slams shut loudly and locks ]
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
LECTER : That 's the same atrocious aftershave you wore in court .
I keep getting it for Christmas .
LECTER : Christmas , yes . Did you get my card ?
I got it , thank you .
LECTER : So nice of the Bureau 's crime lab to forward that .
They wouldn 't give me your home address .
Dr. Bloom sent me your article on surgical addiction ...
in the Journal of Forensic Psychiatry .
LECTER : And ?
Very interesting , even to a layman .
You say you 're a layman .
But it was you who caught me . Wasn 't it , Will ?
LECTER : Do you know how you did it ? will : I got lucky .
I don 't think you believe that .
It 's in the transcript . What does it matter now ?
It doesn 't matter to me , Will .
I need your advice , Dr. Lecter .
LECTER : Birmingham and Atlanta .
You want to know how he 's choosing them , don 't you ?
I thought you 'd have ideas . I want you to tell me them .
Why should I ?
There are things you don 't have .
Research materials . Maybe even computer access .
I 'd speak to the Chief of Staff .
Yes , Dr. Chilton .
Gruesome , isn 't he ?
He fumbles at your head like a freshman pulling at panties .
If you recall , Will ...
our last collaboration ended rather messily .
You 'd get to see the file on this case .
- And there 's another reason . - l 'm all ears .
I thought you might enjoy the challenge .
Find out if you 're smarter than the person I 'm looking for .
[ Slow , ominous instrumental music ]
Then , by implication , you think you 're smarter than I am ...
since it was you who caught me .
I know I 'm not smarter than you .
Then how did you catch me ?
You had disadvantages .
What disadvantages ?
You 're insane .
You 're very tanned , Will .
And your hands are so rough . Not like a cop 's hands anymore .
And that shaving lotion is something a child would select .
Has a little ship on the bottle , does it not ?
And how is young Josh and the lovely Molly ?
They 're always in my thoughts , you know .
You will not persuade me with appeals ...
to my intellectual vanity .
I don 't think I 'll persuade you at all .
You 'll either do it or you won 't .
LECTER : is that the case file ? will : Yes .
With photos ?
Let me keep them , and I might consider it .
No .
Do you dream much , Will ?
Goodbye , Dr. Lecter .
You haven 't threatened to take away my books yet !
Give me the file , then !
And I 'll tell you what I think .
I 'll need one hour . And privacy .
Just like old times , Will ?
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
LECTER : This is a very shy boy , Will .
I 'd love to meet him .
Have you considered that he is disfigured ...
or that he may believe he is disfigured ?
Yeah , the mirrors .
Notice he smashes all the mirrors ...
not just enough to get the pieces he wants .
And , of course , those shards in their eyes ...
so he can see himself there .
That 's interesting .
No , it 's not . You thought of it before .
I had considered it .
- What about the women ? - Dead ?
Mere puppets .
You need to see them living , the way they caught his eye .
That 's impossible .
Almost . Not quite .
What were the yards like ?
Big backyards , fenced , some hedges . Why ?
Because if this pilgrim ...
feels a special relationship with the moon ...
he might like to go outside and look at it .
You ever seen blood in the moonlight ?
It appears quite black .
If one were nude , say , it 'd be better to have ...
outdoor privacy for that sort of thing .
You think the yards are a factor when he selects victims ?
Yes .
And there will be more of them , of course . Victims .
You 'll be wanting lots of these little chinwags ...
- l take it . - l might not have time .
I do .
I have oodles .
I need your opinion now .
Then here 's one :
You stink of fear under that cheap lotion .
You stink of fear , Will , but you 're not a coward !
You fear me , but still you came here .
You fear this shy boy , yet still you seek him out .
Don 't you understand , Will ?
You caught me because we 're very much alike .
Without our imaginations ...
we 'd be like all those other poor dullards .
Fear is the price of our instrument .
But I can help you bear it .
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
- You getting his face ? - Yeah .
Okay , you got it ?
All right , let 's get the fuck out of here .
CRAWFORD : Sure you 're okay ?
Yeah , I 'm okay .
CRAWFORD : What do you think he meant by " see them living " ?
I don 't know , maybe nothing .
It 's hard to separate his bullshit .
But I 'm gonna make another pass at the Leeds ' house .
[ Vaudeville piano music ]
[ Duchess whines ]
CHARLES : All right , Duchess , doll . That 's it .
Show me what you can do .
Who 's that ? Get them , Duchess . Get them , Duch ! Go get them !
Go get them , girl !
Okay .
CHARLES : And action !
Charles ! What are you doing ?
CHARLES : Hey , gang .
valerie : You crazy man .
CHARLES : How is everybody doing ?
valerie : Just home from the store .
susie : Hi , Daddy . CHARLES : That 's my girl .
SEAN : Hi , Daddy . CHARLES : Hi , honey . Billy ?
Hi , Dad .
CHARLES : And sweetie ?
I am not ready for my close-up , Mr. DeMille .
What do you think ?
Get closer . Get closer . Little closer .
I think we 'd better put these kids to bed early tonight .
valerie : They seem tired . Don 't you think ?
CHARLES : Here we are at the pool party .
What are you doing ? Stop it !
You stop it ! I 'm telling my mother on you .
CHARLES : Now I get my kiss ?
- All right , you want a kiss ? - I want one . The romantic kind .
[ Tender instrumental music ]
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
Jacobi House , Birmingham , Al
Won 't nobody get in through here again. I 'll guaran-damn-tee it .
Why didn 't he break in down there ? It 's more hidden .
Hell , that door 's got deadbolts .
Reckon he was in too big a hurry .
No , this one doesn 't hurry .
[ Tense instrumental music ]
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
You sat right here , didn 't you ?
You watched the children bury the cat .
And then you waited for dark .
[ Tense instrumental music ]
[ Dramatic musical surge ]
will : You 're proud . You had to sign your work .
[ Crows cawing ]
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
YOUNG DOLARHYDE : Grandma ? Grandma ?
I 'm sorry .
GRANDMA : I 've never seen a child as dirty and disgusting as you .
Look at you ! You 're soaking wet . Get out of my bed .
YOUNG DOLARHYDE : No . GRANDMA : Go back to your room .
YOUNG DOLARHYDE : You 're hurting me !
GRANDMA : Shut up , you filthy little beast !
I should have put you in an orphanage , grandson or not .
DOLARHYDE : Grandma , don 't hurt me .
You 're hurting me !
GRANDMA : Into the bathroom !
Take off your nightshirt , and wipe yourself off . Hurry up !
Now give me my scissors from the medicine chest .
DOLARHYDE : Please , no !
GRANDMA : Take that filthy thing in your hand . Stretch it out .
DOLARHYDE : No , Grandma .
GRANDMA : Now ! DOLARHYDE : Please !
GRANDMA : Look down . Do you want me to cut it off ? Do you ?
DOLARHYDE : No , Grandma !
GRANDMA : I pledge you my word , Francis ...
if you ever make your bed dirty again ...
I 'll cut it off . Do you understand ?
DOLARHYDE : I 'll be a good boy . I promise .
[ Ominous instrumental music ]
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
[ Eerie instrumental music ]
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
[ Music builds to a crescendo ]
Good morning , Will .
So nice of you to visit again .
He carved this on a tree near the Jacobi house .
With a Buck knife .
The same one later used on Charles Leeds .
Yes .
LECTER : Take a walk with me .
will : He had a second tool , too . A bolt cutter .
He used that to clear his view .
But ?
I don 't think that 's what he brought it for .
It 's too heavy . Too awkward .
And he had to carry it a long way .
And what do we make of that symbol ?
Asian Studies at Langley ...
identified it as a Chinese character .
It appears on a mah-jong piece .
- lt marks the Red Dragon . - Red Dragon . Correct .
This boy begins to interest me .
We don 't know what greater meaning the symbol might have- -
LECTER : Do you like my little exercise cage , Will ?
My so-called lawyer is always nagging Dr. Chilton ...
for better accommodations .
I don 't know which is the greater fool .
Perhaps if you could offer some insight into- -
" A robin redbreast in a cage Puts all heaven in a rage "
Ever been a redbreast , Will ? Of course you have .
I 'm allowed 30 minutes in here , once a week .
Get to the point .
He meant to use the bolt cutter to enter the house ...
but he didn 't .
Instead he broke in through the patio doors .
The noise woke Jacobi , and he had to shoot him on the stairs .
That wasn 't planned . It was sloppy .
And that 's not like him .
We mustn 't judge too harshly , Will .
It was his first time .
Have you never felt a sudden rush of panic ?
Yeah , that 's the fear we talked about .
It takes experience to master it .
You sensed who I was ...
back when I was committing what you call my " crimes . "
Yes .
So you were hurt not by a fault in your perception ...
or your instincts ...
but because you failed to act on them until it was too late .
- You could say that . - But you 're wiser now .
Imagine what you would do , Will , if you could go back in time .
Put two in your head before you could palm that stiletto .
Very good , Will .
You know , I believe we 're making progress .
And that 's what our pilgrim is doing .
He is refining his methods .
He is evolving .
The case file mentioned videos of the Leeds family .
- l 'd like to see those . - No .
- Why not ? - lt would be obscene .
You don 't make it easy , do you ? Still , one aims to please .
I 'll call you if I think of anything else .
Would you perhaps like to leave me your home number ?
[ Loud buzzer sounds ]
- That 's the end of our session . - For now .
It was only his first time .
Already in Atlanta he did much better .
Rest assured , my dear Will ...
this one will give you plenty of exercise .
[ Unnerving instrumental music ]
LECTER : My love to Molly and Josh , goodbye .
BARNEY : Go to the back of the cell , Dr. Lecter . Face the wall .
BARNEY : If you turn around before the lock snaps ...
you 'll get a dart .
BARNEY : Understood ? LECTER : Yes .
You got ten minutes to talk to your lawyer .
BARNEY : Starting now . LECTER : Thanks so much , Barney .
LAWYER : Hello , Dr. Lecter ?
I have those documents you requested me- -
[ Dial tone ]
[ Rotary telephone dialling clicks ]
" Robes , Robespierre , Robin .
" Robin , call for ... . Robin , fainting ... .
" Redbreast in a cage . " 406.9 .
" A robin redbreast in a cage Puts all heaven in a rage "
Yes , that 's it .
William Blake . Auguries of Innocence .
Think you got it ?
Yeah , we should have .
We have some books of Blake 's paintings , too .
- Want to see them ? - Yeah . Thanks .
TEMP : Psychology Department ...
University of Chicago . Dr. Bloom 's office .
Hi . This is Bob Greer at Blaine and Edwards Publishing .
Dr. Bloom asked me to send The Psychiatrist and the Law ...
to Will Graham .
His assistant was supposed to give me ...
the address and phone number , but , darn it , she never did .
TEMP : I 'm just a temp . Linda will be in on Monday .
I have to catch FedEx in about five minutes .
I hate to bother Dr. Bloom about it ...
because he told Linda to send it ...
and I don 't want to get her into trouble .
It 's right there in the Rolodex , or whatever .
I 'll dance at your wedding if you read it to me .
TEMP : I don 't know . I 'm really not supposed to .
Be a darling and flip that old rascal ...
I won 't take up any more of your time .
Graham , Will .
TEMP : All right . Just a minute .
" Gibson , Gordon , Graham . "
It doesn 't give a home address .
What does it have , dear ?
TEMP : " FBI , 935 Pennsylvania Avenue Northwest , Washington , D.C. "
LECTER : Yeah ? TEMP : And let 's see .
Here it is .
" P.O. Box 3680 , Marathon , Florida . "
LECTER : Marathon . TEMP : Yes .
That 's fine . You 're an angel .
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
I 'm Francis Dolarhyde .
I 've come for the package of infrared .
Right . Put your back against the door and come ...
forward three steps till you feel tile under your feet .
And there 's a stool just on the left .
Same Mr. D who 's head of Tech Services , am I right ?
I 'm Reba McClane .
Just a second more and I will get you some light .
REBA : Okay , here we go .
So , what do you need the ir for ?
It 's for the zoo .
They want to photograph the nocturnal animals .
That 's great. I love animals . I got to warn you , though .
This stuff is pretty sensitive . It can be mean to handle .
But I guess I don 't need to tell you that .
Hey , Reba . Oh , Mr. D. Whoa !
I 'm not interrupting anything , am I ?
No , Ralph .
It 's starting to spritz outside .
I 'll give you a lift home ?
You ride a motorcycle .
How 's that gonna help me with the rain ?
I thought maybe we 'd stop off someplace ...
have ourselves a little sundowner .
- l 've already got a ride . - lt 's cool .
That 's cool . No problemo .
If there 's anything I hate worse than pity , it 's fake pity .
Especially from a walking hard-on like Ralph Mandy .
- Sorry . - l have no pity .
Ride with me !
Thanks , but I take the bus all the time .
Mandy is a fool . Ride with me ...
for my pleasure .
You want to come in ? I 'll fix us a drink .
- Maybe another time . - l will come in .
When is the zoo project ?
- Maybe next week . They 'll call . - l love zoos .
In fact one of my earliest memories is seeing a cougar ...
when I was about five .
I didn 't lose my sight till I was seven . Diphtheria .
Could you hand me that knife ?
I 've always tried to hang on to what that cougar looked like .
But by now , to tell the truth , what I see in my head ...
is probably not in the least bit like a cougar .
It 's more like a donkey or a goat .
You know , sometimes I 'm not so sure I really saw him .
Maybe he 's just something I dreamed up .
You okay ?
You don 't say much , do you ?
No , I guess not .
Let 's talk about something and get it out of the way , okay ?
I can hear that you 've had ...
some kind of soft palate repair .
But I understand you fine because you speak very well .
If you don 't want to talk to me , that 's cool .
But I hope that you will , because ...
I know what it 's like to have people ...
always thinking that you 're different .
That 's good .
May I touch your face ?
I want to know if you 're smiling or frowning .
I want to know whether I should just shut up or not .
Take my word that I 'm smiling .
I have to go .
If I offended you , I didn 't mean to .
No .
F.B.l. Headquarters , Washington , D.C.
will : I don 't know what they were like .
It 'd help if I could see some of their personal effects .
Diaries , letters . Do you have those things ?
I sure do. I mean , other than ...
one or two little keepsakes Niles Jacobi got .
That would be Mr. Jacobi 's surviving son by his first wife ?
Yes . As their executor , I keep all that stuff in the office ...
along with some of the smaller valuables , till after probate .
But the Birmingham P.D. ' s been all through it .
Could you pack those things and ship them up to me ?
I hate to ask . I know it 's a pain in the ass .
Hell ...
probate judge is an old golfing buddy of mine .
Son , just tell me you 're gonna nail that son of a bitch .
We 're doing our best .
Hey , thanks , Mr. Metcalf .
A note hidden in Lecter 's cell . Sounds like a fan letter .
Might 've been mailed by the Tooth Fairy .
He wants Lecter 's approval .
He 's curious about you . He 's asking questions .
I 've scrambled a chopper .
Does Lecter know we have the note ?
CRAWFORD : Not yet . It was found in a routine cleanup .
will : They don 't open his mail ?
CRAWFORD : Need a warrant . X-rays only .
will : Where 's Lecter ? CRAWFORD : The holding cage .
will : Can he see his cell ?
CRAWFORD : No . But he 's been there almost half an hour .
He 'll soon start to wonder what 's wrong .
We got to buy time , Jack .
CRAWFORD : Dr. Chilton . CHlLTON : Yes ?
Call your building superintendent ...
or engineer , whoever 's in charge .
Tell him to pull the circuit breakers on Lecter 's hall .
Have the super walk down the hall past the cell ...
carrying tools .
He 'll be in a hurry , pissed off , too busy to answer questions .
And don 't forget : Don 't touch the note , okay ?
Graham 's on his way .
Listen up ! We 've got a note coming in on the fly ...
possibly from the Tooth Fairy . Number One Priority .
It has to go back to Lecter 's cell within the hour ...
unmarked .
We 'll need Hair and Fibre , Latent Prints , then Documents .
I 'll walk it through myself . Let 's go , people !
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
DOLARHYDE [ Voiceover ] : My dear Dr. Lecter . : I wanted to tell you ...
I 'm delighted ...
that you 've taken an interest in me .
And when I learned of your vast correspondence , I thought . :
" Dare I ? " Of course I do .
I don 't believe you 'll tell them who I am .
Besides , what particular body I currently occupy is trivial .
The important thing is what I am becoming .
I know that you alone can understand this transformation .
I have some things I 'd love to show you .
If circumstances permit , I hope we can correspond .
I have admired you for years and have ...
a complete collection of your press notices .
Actually , I think of them as unfair reviews .
As unfair as mine .
They do like to sling demeaning nicknames , don 't they ?
" The Tooth Fairy . " What could be more inappropriate ?
It would shame me for you to read that , if I didn 't know ...
you had suffered the same distortions in the press .
I 'm fed up with this bloody stupid building !
Every day something breaking .
SUPER : I swear they ought to tear the whole fucking place down .
- How much longer do we have ? - Ten minutes , max .
BOWMAN : Instructions for answering ...
were probably in the section Lecter tore out .
Why not just throw the whole note away ?
It was full of compliments .
He couldn 't bear to part with them .
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
Now we can mash just a little .
You 're so sly .
BOWMAN : But so am I .
Aniline dyes and coloured inks are transparent to infrared .
These could be the tips of " T 's " here and here .
On the end , that 's a " P , " or possibly an " R. "
Maybe this is where he 's telling Lecter how to answer him .
There 's only one way to carry on a conversation ...
that 's one-way blind .
Publication . Wait a minute .
We know this guy reads the Tattler .
That 's in his note , right ?
The Tooth Fairy , they made that up .
BOWMAN : Three " T 's " and an " R " in " Tattler . "
How do you communicate through a tabloid ?
- You got what ? News stories . - Personals .
Maybe he wants Lecter to answer him through the personals ?
- That could be it . - We need proofs of the pages ...
before the next Tattler 's published !
CRAWFORD : I 'm on it !
DOLARHYDE : Investigator Graham interests me .
Not your standard gumshoe , is he ?
More alert .
Purposeful looking .
You should have taught him not to meddle .
Forgive the stationery .
I chose it because it 'll dissolve very quickly ...
if you should have to swallow it .
If I hear from you , next time I might send you something wet .
Until then , dear Doctor ...
I remain your most ...
avid fan .
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
CRAWFORD : The Tattler got an ad order signed 666 ...
Baltimore postmark on the envelope .
It 's set to run this afternoon .
Chicago field office is sending the text through now .
- " Dear Pilgrim . " - That 's it .
Lecter called him a pilgrim when we talked .
" You honour me . You 're very beautiful . " Christ !
" l offer 100 prayers for your safety .
" Find help in John 6 : 22 , 8 : 16 ...
" 9 : 1 , Luke 1 : 7 . "
- Code . - Has to be .
We 've got 19 minutes to get in a message if we can break this .
The Tattler can 't hold its presses any longer .
It 's simple .
They only needed cover against casual readers .
- l 'm thinking it 's a book code . - Code ?
The first numeral ...
" 100 prayers , " may be the page number .
The numbers after could be line and letter . But what book ?
- Bible ? - No , he 's got " Galatians 15 : 2 . "
It has only six chapters .
Same with " Jonah 6 : 8 . " lt has four chapters .
He wasn 't using a Bible .
Then the Tooth Fairy named the book to use .
He specified it in his note , in the part Lecter tore out .
BOWMAN : It would appear so .
What about sweating Lecter ? In a mental hospital ...
- l would think drugs- - - No .
They tried sodium amytal on him three years ago , to find out ...
where he buried the Princeton student .
He gave them a recipe for dip .
If we sweat him , we lose the connection .
If the Tooth Fairy picked the book ...
he knew Lecter would have it in his cell .
- Can we get a list of his books ? - From Chilton , maybe .
No ! Wait ! Rankin and Willingham , when they tossed his cell ...
took Polaroids so they could put everything back in place .
Ask them to meet me with pictures of his bookshelves !
CRAWFORD : Where ? BOWMAN : The Library !
I 'm leery of letting Lecter 's message run ...
without knowing what it says .
I say let this one run . We keep working on the code .
At least it 'll encourage the Fairy to contact him again .
What if it encourages him to do something besides write ?
I don 't like this any better than you .
But it 's our best shot .
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
National Tattler Building , Chicago , ll
Library of Congress , Washington , D.C.
[ Eerie instrumental music ]
BOWMAN : Oh , my God !
Hello ?
Jack , it 's Lloyd Bowman . I solved the code .
You need to know what it says right now .
Okay , Lloyd .
It says , " Graham home , Marathon , Florida .
" Save yourself . Kill them all . "
will : Yeah ? CRAWFORD : Bowman just broke the code .
- What does it say ? - l 'll tell you in a second .
Now , listen to me . Everything is okay .
I 've taken care of it . Stay on the phone when I tell you .
Tell me now .
Lecter gave the bastard your home address .
CRAWFORD : Wait .
[ Faint thump ]
[ Door opening ]
[ Harrowing instrumental music ]
Mum ?
AGENT [ Shouting ] : Head down , ma 'am .
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
[ Tender instrumental music ]
MOLLY : is he after you now ?
will : No , Lecter just suggested it to him .
I hate this , Molly .
I 'm sorry .
- lt 's a sick feeling . - l know it is .
But you 'll be safe here .
Crawford 's brother owns this place .
No one in the world knows you 're here .
I 'd just as soon not talk about Crawford .
AGENT : What are you using as bait ? JOSH : Sometimes I use worms .
AGENT : You like those ?
Beneath the yellow folder ...
you 'll find your latest rejection slip ...
from the archives .
LECTER : It was brought to me by mistake with some of my archives mail .
I 'm afraid I opened it without looking .
Sorry .
I think we 'll remove Dr. Lecter 's toilet seat .
[ Gunshots ]
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
CRAWFORD : Atlanta P.D. nailed him .
He had a fake Bureau id ...
and was trying to get the Leeds family autopsy photos .
It 's a Federal beef , so Atlanta kicked him back to us .
Personally ...
I 'd like nothing better than to see the dirt sandwich ...
pulling five at Leavenworth .
But maybe there 's a better way to handle this .
Yeah ? What 's that ?
I think we ought to give him a story .
will : The Tooth Fairy 's ugly ...
and he 's impotent with members of the opposite sex .
Also , he sexually molests his male victims .
While they 're alive ?
will : Sorry , I can 't go into those details .
But we do also speculate ...
that he 's the product of an incestuous home .
No wonder the creep 's such a loser , right ?
That 's a tip we got from Dr. Lecter , by the way .
So it 's true that Lecter 's helping with your investigation ?
will : Yes , it 's true .
The Doctor was offended a bottom-feeding lowlife like ...
the Tooth Fairy would consider himself in the same league .
[ Lounds laughs ]
Okay , tell me about this place you got here .
Will , your little Washington hideaway .
This is an apartment I 'm borrowing ...
till this creep goes down in flames .
I keep copies of the evidence so I can work on it at night .
Make sure you can read the name on that building .
PHOTOGRAPHER : Yeah .
All right , I got enough .
Just remember , I scratch your back , you scratch mine .
If my story draws the Fairy in an attack on Graham ...
and you nail the scumbag , I get an exclusive .
Fuck you , Lounds .
When we see the story , we 'll consider what to do ...
about your sealed indictment .
All right , it was a pleasure doing business with you , chumps .
will : I feel like I need a shower .
You okay with this ?
Better he comes after me than Molly and Josh .
So , yeah , I 'm okay with it .
I wish we had something better ...
but there 's only ten days till the next full moon .
We 've got to rattle his cage .
CRAWFORD : We 'll stake out this apartment , put snipers on the rooftops .
You 'll have a moving box tail , 24 / 7 , in your car ...
on the street , wherever you go .
You 'll wear the Kevlar at all times . No exceptions .
You again ?
Come back at 4 : 00 a.m. when I open , all right ?
Hey , I told you !
DOLARHYDE : What ?
You told me what ?
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
LOUNDS : Fucking dickhead !
Is that your fucking name on the sign ?
[ Lounds yelps in pain ]
[ Harrowing instrumental music ]
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
[ Suspenseful musical surges ]
[ Lounds panting heavily ]
LOUNDS : Where am I ?
What am I doing here ?
DOLARHYDE : Atoning , Mr. Lounds .
LOUNDS : I haven 't seen your face .
I couldn 't possibly identify you .
I work for the National Tattler .
It would pay ...
a big reward for me .
I mean , a half a million ...
or a million , maybe .
DOLARHYDE : Do you know who I am , Mr. Lounds ?
No .
And I don 't want to know .
You know , believe me .
DOLARHYDE : According to you , I 'm a vicious , perverted sexual failure ...
a " bottom-feeding lowlife " ...
who 's about to " go down in flames . "
I think you know now , don 't you ?
Yes .
DOLARHYDE : Do you understand what I 'm doing , Mr. Lounds ?
No .
But I would like to .
I really want to understand ...
and then all my readers could understand , too .
DOLARHYDE : I am not a man .
I began as one ...
but each being that I change makes me ...
more than a man ...
as you will witness .
I don 't need to see you . No .
But you must , Mr. Lounds .
You 're a reporter .
You 're here to report .
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
Open your eyes and look at me .
No .
If you won 't open them ...
I 'll staple your eyelids to your forehead .
No !
DOLARHYDE : Open your eyes !
Oh , my dear God Jesus !
Oh , God !
[ Dolarhyde grunts loudly ]
Do you want to know what I am ?
More than anything .
I was afraid to ask .
DOLARHYDE : Do you see now ?
Yeah , I see .
Oh , God .
DOLARHYDE : Mrs. Jacobi in human form .
DOLARHYDE : Do you see ? LOUNDS : Yes .
DOLARHYDE : Mrs. Leeds in human form .
- Do you see ? - Yes .
- Mrs . Jacobi changing . - Oh , my God .
Mrs. Leeds changing .
Do you see ?
DOLARHYDE : Mrs. Jacobi reborn .
Mrs. Leeds reborn .
- Do you see ? - Please , no .
No ? No what ?
Not me .
Why did you write lies , Mr. Lounds ?
Graham told me to lie .
LOUNDS : It wasn 't me .
- Will you tell the truth now ? - Yes !
About me ?
- My work ? - Oh , yes .
My becoming ?
Yeah .
I am the Dragon , and you call me insane !
You are privy to a great becoming ...
and you recognise nothing .
You are an ant in the afterbirth .
It is in your nature to do one thing correctly .
Before me , you rightly tremble .
But fear is not what you owe me , Mr. Lounds .
You owe me awe .
Read .
DOLARHYDE : That 's all , Mr. Lounds .
You did very well .
Will you let me go now ?
DOLARHYDE : Soon .
There 's one more way I can help you to better understand .
I want to understand .
I do . And I 'm really gonna be fair ...
from now on .
You know that .
Hello ?
LOUNDS : Oh , God , no !
[ Lounds screaming in pain ]
[ Rusty wheels squeaking ]
LOUNDS [ Recording ] : I have had a great privilege .
I have seen with ...
wonder and awe the strength of the Great Red Dragon .
He has helped me to understand his splendour ...
and now I want to serve him .
He knows you made me lie , Will Graham .
Because I was forced to lie ...
he will be more merciful to me than to you .
Hello ?
Oh , God , no !
[ Lounds screaming in pain on recording ]
[ Silence ]
We can let this tie us up in knots ...
or we can learn from it .
Maybe even use it to catch the bastard .
He had to have a van or panel truck ...
to move Lounds around in that big old wheelchair .
Go on .
He had to already have the wheelchair ...
or know where to get one fast .
It 's an antique , not something you 'd find in the house .
Does it strike anybody that he set this up in a hurry ?
The Tattler comes off the press Monday night .
By Tuesday morning he 's in Chicago , snatching Lounds .
He either lives in the Chicago area ...
or he 's within a driving radius of ...
call it six hours .
Find out in this area where the Tattler was available ...
for early distribution Monday night .
Start with airports , all-night newsstands .
Maybe a newsie remembers an odd customer .
Lloyd , this cassette , enhance the audio .
Maybe you can pick up something in the background .
That wheelchair ...
I want the maker , date , possible sources .
Graham and I will coordinate from Chicago . Let 's hustle .
Look , there 's not gonna be any answers in Chicago , Jack .
Okay ? I mean , Lounds , that was a bonus .
That was a chance to show off . It doesn 't even fit his pattern .
The Leeds and the Jacobis are what he needs .
I think I should go back to Baltimore .
After what he tried to pull ?
Lecter picked up on something in the missing part of the note .
Not a name , but something , enough to narrow the search .
Even if he did , he won 't tell you .
Not unless I can offer him something .
LECTER [ Voiceover ] : Congratulations .
That was most artistic , the way you disposed of Mr. Lounds .
Your cell looks bigger with no books in it .
Does it ?
I hadn 't noticed .
will : Oh , you will .
I have other resources .
Tell me , Will . Did you enjoy it ?
Your first murder ?
Of course you did . Why shouldn 't it feel good ?
It does to God .
Why , only last week in Texas , he dropped a church roof ...
on the heads of 34 of his worshippers ...
as they were grovelling through a hymn .
He wouldn 't begrudge you one journalist .
Put me next to him , Doctor .
You and some SWAT team ?
Oh , Will . Where 's the fun in that ?
He 'll have to take his chances , too .
A roof can fall on anybody .
But not on Molly and Josh , I take it .
Not yet , anyway .
First he kills the pet , then the family .
Freddy was your pet .
They 're safe now .
No one will ever be safe around you , Will .
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
Clever work on his note , by the way .
And that blackout was an especially nice touch .
What else was in that note , Doctor ?
Put me next to him !
That 's what you want , isn 't it ?
To help him succeed where you failed ?
Twice ?
Give him a chance to kill me .
Go on , then .
Seduce me with your wares .
Full restoration of your privileges .
Plus computer access to the AMA archives .
One hour a week under supervision , of course ...
but it 's a one-time offer .
It expires the minute I walk out of here .
Bit measly , don 't you think ?
Turn it down , then . See what terms you get from Chilton .
Are these threats , William ?
I 'm waiting , Doctor . Or maybe you 've got nothing left to sell .
A little sample , then . Why not ?
- Seen the Blake , have you ? - Yes .
No , you 've looked but not seen .
Transformation is the key .
The man-dragon ...
his ugliness transformed by power .
Look for a military record with combat training .
Look for extensive tattooing ...
and corrective surgery , most likely to the face .
Come on , I 'm past that already and you know it .
Give me what I need .
How is he choosing the women ?
I 've already suggested how . The answer was in front of you .
- You looked but didn 't see . - Bullshit ! No riddles !
Just tell me .
No !
LECTER : It 's your turn .
I asked you before for a small courtesy ...
and you responded rudely .
Before I tell you anything more ...
you will make certain arrangements for me .
What kind of arrangements ?
Oh , nothing much .
Shall we say dinner and a show ?
You ready to tell me what kind of outing this is ?
Nope .
You 're just full of surprises , aren 't you , D ?
Yep .
WARFlELD : He 's about six feet away .
Can you smell him ?
Yeah .
Now , he 's a little noisy , but he 's sedated , I assure you .
Doctor Hassler 's about to fix his broken tooth .
Glad you could come , Ms. McClane .
We appreciate the infrared film , by the way .
WARFlELD : Two more steps .
I 'll put your left hand on the edge of the table .
Now , he 's right in front of you .
Take your time .
[ Tiger bays drowsily ]
- D ? - l 'm here .
You go ahead .
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
[ Tiger growls sleepily ]
Here .
Why don 't you try this ?
[ Strong heartbeat ]
[ Clock ticking ]
Nine steps from the front door to the clock ...
and three more to this room .
Sorry . Force of habit .
[ Jazz music plays ]
That beautiful tiger , this house , this music ... .
l don 't think anybody knows you at all , D.
Everybody wonders about you , though .
Especially the women .
What do they want to know ?
They find you ...
very mysterious and interesting .
Did they tell you how I look ?
They said that you have a remarkable body .
That you 're very sensitive about your face but you shouldn 't be .
Oh , and ...
they asked me if ...
you are as strong as you look .
And ?
I said I didn 't know .
[ Record stops playing ]
[ Seductive jazz music plays ]
Where the hell are you , D ?
Here you are .
Do you want to know what I think about it ?
Now , would you show me where the bathroom is ?
[ Slow , suspenseful instrumental music ]
[ Seductive jazz music plays ]
I have to do a little work .
- lf l 'm keeping you from work ... - No .
- ... I 'll go . - l want you to be here .
I do. lt 's just a tape I need to watch .
It won 't take long .
- Do you need to hear it , too ? - No .
May I keep the music ?
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
What 's it about ?
Some people I 'm going to meet .
So then ...
it 's what ? It 's a corporate promo ? Some kind of homework ?
It 's homework . Yeah .
That 's a good idea .
It 's so important to be prepared .
My God , are you ever !
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
[ Tense instrumental music ]
[ Dolarhyde whimpers in panic ]
DOLARHYDE : No. I won 't give her to you . No .
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
Please , just for a little while .
[ Crying ] No ! You 're hurting me !
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
No ...
she 's nice .
She 's okay .
[ Climactic instrumental music ]
I had a really terrific time last night .
But this morning you seem like a different person .
- ls something wrong ? - l have to go now .
- l have to go away . - Where ?
On a trip .
- When will I see you again ? - Reba , you have to get out . Now .
METCALF [ Voiceover ] : Dear Mr. Graham . :
Here are the Jacobis' personal effects , as discussed .
I hope these things might help you .
Good hunting . Byron Metcalf .
[ Soft piano music ]
CRAWFORD : How many more times are we going to watch this ?
will : " See them living , " he said , " right in front of you . "
It 's something about these home movies .
Lecter keeps saying , " You looked , but didn 't see . "
CRAWFORD : Lecter says a lot of things .
Sad damn thing . But we already knew that .
We can 't afford to let Lecter waste our- -
No . Again .
MS. HARPER : Your dissertation must be nearly finished , Mr. Crane .
DOLARHYDE : Nearly .
It 's nice to be able to connect a face with a name ...
after all our correspondence .
But , you know , you don 't look like I imagined you looked .
What did you think I looked like ?
Different .
[ Soft piano music ]
[ Yells surprise ]
[ Mouths ] Thank you .
Right there ! There .
will : That 's what he wanted the bolt cutter for .
To cut that padlock and go in through the basement .
will : But that 's a different door .
I don 't get it . The one I saw was flush steel with deadbolts .
Jacobi had a new door installed . Beginning of January , I think .
It 's in here somewhere .
CRAWFORD : Think he cased the house with the old door ?
He brought the bolt cutter , didn 't he ?
He was sure he 'd need it .
Why case it two months in advance and not check it ?
I don 't know . He was ready with the bolt cutter ...
like at the Leeds ' house .
There he was ready with a glass cutter .
He must 've seen the glass when he walked in the neighbourhood .
No . You can 't see that door from the yard .
There 's a porch lattice in the way .
Jack , he knew the inside of the houses .
Remarkable , isn 't it ?
Two hundred years old .
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
Yet so fresh .
So vivid .
[ Soft piano music ]
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
He almost looks alive , doesn 't he ?
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
[ Harrowing instrumental music ]
We 've just gotten a report here from the ... .
[ Woman screams ]
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
CRAWFORD : Do you still have the Jacobis ' check stubs ...
and credit card statements ?
We 're looking for any kind of service call or purchase ...
that might 've required a stranger ...
to enter the house .
CRAWFORD : A repairman , delivery guy . METCALF : Anybody in the house .
CRAWFORD : Yeah . METCALF : We checked .
CRAWFORD : I know we checked that ...
but now we got to go back to before January .
METCALF : Last year 's purchase orders . CRAWFORD : Yeah .
will : No collar . CRAWFORD : But please hurry. lt 's urgent .
No collar .
CRAWFORD : Metcalf says- - will : No collar .
The dog had no collar in a neighbourhood of dogs ...
but he knew which was theirs .
Same with the Jacobis ' cat . No collar , but he knew .
will : He knew about the padlock . He knew about the pane of glass .
He knew the layout . He knew how to get in .
Every goddamn thing he needed to know was on this ... .
Oh , Jesus .
is Metcalf still on the phone ? Give it !
Byron , it 's Graham .
You said Niles Jacobi took a few keepsakes . Do you have a list ?
METCALF : Yeah , right here .
I need to know if something he took was a home video .
A full-length VHS tape , compiled from shorter tapes .
METCALF : I see one videotape . will : Yes ?
METCALF : But it says , " Meet the Jacobis . "
It 's Chromalux .
CRAWFORD : We just got a fax .
An incident at the Brooklyn Museum .
A guy attacked two employees , and get this ...
ate the Blake painting .
will : What ?
That 's him. lt 's got to be .
If that painting meant so much to him , why destroy it ?
And why didn 't he kill those two women at the museum ?
They both got a good look at him .
Maybe he 's trying to stop .
[ Suspenseful instrumental music ]
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
Mr. Crawford , all you 've got is a hunch .
I 've got 382 employees , and they 've got a union .
I can 't just turn you loose on their files .
Not without a court order .
There are privacy issues . The company 's exposure .
One of the employees has already killed 1 1 people ...
that we know of .
If he gets away tonight ...
what 's the company 's exposure on that ?
- l 'll get our lawyers here- - - We don 't have time for that .
will : Listen !
We 're looking for a white male , 25 to 35 ...
- right-handed with brown hair . - No--
Listen ! Please . He 's strong . He 's possibly a bodybuilder .
He might have some kind of facial disfigurement .
He drives a van or a panel truck .
That sounds like Mr. D.
Oh , my God .
Who 's Mr. D ?
Francis Dolarhyde , Manager of Technical Services .
What does he do exactly ?
He maintains the equipment for tape transfers .
Would he have access to people 's home videotapes ?
He has access to every tape that comes through here .
Thanks for dinner , and thanks for letting me vent .
Look , no problemo .
Reba , listen , I know it 's not my place to say this ... .
Go on .
Well , if Dolarhyde is really as moody as you say he is ...
maybe you ought to keep some distance .
I mean , what do you really know about the guy ?
I appreciate your concern , Ralph . Really .
And I promise I 'll give it some thought .
- Hey , have a great vacation . - Thanks .
- See you in a week . - Good night .
[ Ominous instrumental music ]
RALPH : I had a great time . REBA : Good night .
RALPH : Good night !
[ Ominous instrumental music ]
Ralph , just ' cause I 'm feeling vulnerable- -
[ Harrowing instrumental music ]
DOLARHYDE : Wake up .
You wandered around in the house while I was asleep , didn 't you ?
REBA : What ?
The other night , did you find something odd ?
Did you take it and show it to somebody ? Did you do that ?
D ? What is it ?
What 's happening ?
- Sit still or he 'll hear us ! - Who will ?
He 's upstairs .
He wants you , Reba .
I thought he was gone , but now he 's back .
D , you 're scaring me .
I didn 't want to give you to him .
I did a thing for you today so he couldn 't have you .
I was wrong .
You made me weak and then you hurt me .
[ Police car sirens ]
No .
No , you can 't have her !
Please don 't let him have me .
REBA : You won 't .
I 'm for you .
You like me. I know you like me . Take me with you .
Take you with me ? Yes . Put out your hand .
Feel this . That 's a shotgun .
A 1 2-gauge magnum . Do you know what it 'll do ?
I wish I could have trusted you . I wanted to trust you .
You felt so good !
So did you .
- Please don 't hurt me now . - lt 's all over for me .
[ Reba gasps in panic ]
- Where are you ? - l can 't leave you to him .
DOLARHYDE : Do you know what he 'll do ? He 'll bite you to death .
He 'll hurt you so bad ! I can 't let that happen .
- lt 's better if you go with me . - Yes , God , get us out of here !
- l 'll shoot you and then myself . - Oh , no .
- l have to shoot you . - No ... .
l can 't do it .
[ Screaming ] D !
[ Gunshot ]
[ Coughs and pants heavily ]
[ Clock chimes ]
REBA : Three steps to the clock .
From the clock to the door , nine more .
Oh , God .
[ Climactic instrumental music ]
What is that ? What the hell is that ?
That 's the place .
Goddamn it !
All units , that 's his house that 's burning .
[ Dramatic instrumental music , sirens blaring ]
fbi !
Francis Dolarhyde ! Where is he ?
He 's in there . He is dead .
You know that ?
He shot himself in the face . I put my hand in it .
He set fire to the house . He was on the floor , and l- -
You all right ?
will : That 's all I need .
I 'd like to come back before I leave town .
will : See how you 're doing . REBA : Sure , why not ?
Who could resist a charmer like me ?
You know , whatever part of him was still human ...
was only kept alive because of you .
You probably saved some lives .
You didn 't draw a freak . Okay ?
You drew a man with a freak on his back .
I should have known .
No , sometimes you don 't . Trust me , I 've been there .
Listen to me . There was plenty wrong with Dolarhyde ...
but there 's nothing wrong with you .
Except your hair .
Your hair is a train wreck .
Can we please do something about that ?
For next time , maybe ? Please ?
That would be nice .
REBA : Thank you . will : Just get some rest .
will : You 're gonna be fine .
ANNOUNCER : Dr. Voss , please call Pharmacy 4421 .
We found this in his safe .
Thought you might want to take the first look .
CRAWFORD : You 've earned it .
[ Melancholy instrumental music ]
will : When I read his journal , it was sad .
It was just so sad .
I couldn 't help feeling sorry for him .
He wasn 't born a monster .
This guy was made one through years of abuse .
- Hey . - Hey , Dad , can we make s 'mores ?
- S 'mores ? - Yeah , s 'mores .
- Yeah , you 're on . - All right .
- Go look in the pantry . - Okay .
[ Telephone rings ]
Crawford .
price : Those remains you found in the rubble .
- They 're not Dolarhyde 's . - What are you talking about ?
- His damn dentures were there . - But not his bones .
Wrong DNA .
Then whose are they ?
Saint Louis P.D. is looking for ...
a Chromalux employee named Ralph Mandy .
He should be on vacation , so nobody missed him for a week .
- What is taking him so long ? - Are you kidding ?
It takes him 20 minutes to get out of bed in the morning .
Yeah , but now I have a serious marshmallow jones .
Josh , what are you doing ?
[ Suspenseful musical surge ]
[ Telephone rings ]
MOLLY [ Recording ] : We can 't come to the phone . You know the deal .
Wait for the beep .
CRAWFORD [ On machine ] : It 's Jack . It 's Dolarhyde . He 's still alive .
I 'm scrambling everything that rolls or flies ...
but they 'll take time to arrive .
Will ?
Christ , Will , where are you ?
[ Ominous instrumental music ]
[ Music builds to a crescendo ]
Drop it . Do it now , gumshoe .
Your son is about to change .
Then your wife .
You can watch .
Then I 'll take care of you .
Look at you .
I 've never seen a child as disgusting as you !
You pissed your pants ? How dare you !
You dirty little beast . You want me to cut it off ?
Want me to do that , you little freak ?
You want me to cut it off ?
Do you ? Don 't cry at me , you little faggot !
Apologise ! Say , " l 'm sorry , Daddy ! I 'm a dirty little beast .
" l 'm a freak . " Say it !
- No . - Say it !
- Dad ! - Say it , or I will cut it off !
will : " l 'm a dirty little beast .
" Freak ! Harelip !
" And no one will ever love me . "
[ Shouting ] Josh , run ! Run !
[ Raging instrumental music ]
Get down !
You okay ?
[ Sudden silence ]
MOLLY [ From downstairs ] : Josh ? JOSH : Mum ?
MOLLY : Will ?
Where are you guys ?
I thought I heard some kind of ... .
Will ?
Molly , get down !
MOLLY : Will !
[ Molly gasps and sobs ]
[ Ominous instrumental music ]
will : [ Gasps ] Shoot ... .
What ?
Shoot him . Shoot him .
[ Climactic instrumental music ]
[ Sirens wail ]
JOSH : Mummy ?
LECTER [ Voiceover ] : My dear Will . : You must be healed by now .
On the outside , at least .
I hope you 're not too ugly .
What a collection of scars you have !
Never forget who gave you the best of them .
And be grateful .
Our scars have the power to remind us the past was real .
We live in a primitive time , don 't we , Will ?
Neither savage nor wise .
Half measures are the curse of it .
A rational society would either kill me or put me to some use .
Do you dream much , Will ? I think of you often .
Your old friend , Hannibal Lecter .
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]
CHlLTON : Hannibal ? There 's someone here to see you .
Wants to ask a few questions . I said you 'd probably refuse .
A young woman . Says she 's from the fbi .
Though she 's far too pretty , if you ask me .
I 'll tell her you said no .
What is her name ?
[ Dramatic instrumental music ]